Chapter 15, Practical Application. Take everything you've learned and use it.
练习 15-1：美日贸易摩擦。听下面节选并比较两个版本。
Exercise 15-1, Practical Application. U .S.-Japan Trade Friction. Listen to the
请听下面节选并比较两个版本；这里开始正文。
following excerpt and compare the two versions. Forty years after the end of
World War II, Japan and the U.S. are again engaged in conflict. Trade frictions,
which began as minor irritants in an otherwise smooth relationship in the
1960s, have gradually escalated over the years. The conflict is more dangerous than
it appears because its real nature is partially hidden. It masquerades as a
banal and sometimes grubby dispute over widgets, with the stakes being whether
American or Japanese big business makes more money. In truth, the issue is
strategic and geopolitical in nature. Japan is once again challenging the U.S.
only this time the issue is not China or the Pacific but world industrial and
technological leadership and the military and economic powers which have always been
its corollaries.